A Pawsome 3D Adventure.
Alpha and Omega is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Anthony Bell.
Two young wolves at opposite ends of their pack's social order are thrown together into a
foreign land and need each other to return home, but love complicates everything.
Humphrey (voice), played by Justin Long.
Kate (voice), played by Hayden Panettiere.
Tony (voice), played by Dennis Hopper.
Winston (voice), played by Danny Glover.
Marcel (voice), played by Larry Miller.
Paddy / Mooch (voice), played by Eric Price.
Alpha and Omega is a 2010 American animated romantic comedy
adventure film directed by Anthony Bell and Ben Gluck.
Starring the voices of Justin Long, Hayden Panettiere, Dennis Hopper, Danny Glover and Christina Ricci, the
film was written by Christopher Denk and Steve Moore, based on a story by Moore and Gluck.
The film sets around two young Rocky Mountain wolves named Kate (Panettiere) and Humphrey (Long)
who fall in love with each other, but are on the opposite ends of their pack.
However, when Kate and Humphrey learn that they got relocated to Idaho for repopulation, they must work
together to get back to Jasper National Park before a war slowly begins to emerge between both packs.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2010, and
was released nationwide in 2-D and 3-D on September 17, 2010, by Lionsgate.
Alpha and Omega was a box-office success, grossing $50.5 million against a budget of
$20 million, but received generally negative reviews from critics.
Despite its negative reception, however, it has received a cult following.
The film was dedicated to Hopper, as he died from prostate
cancer four months before it was released.
The film eventually turned into a franchise of 7 direct-to-video sequels including Alpha
and Omega 2: A Howl-iday Adventure, which was released on October 8, 2013.
Another sequel, The Great Wolf Games, was released on March 25, 2014.
The Legend of the Saw Tooth Cave was released on September 23, 2014.
Family Vacation was released to DVD on August 4, 2015.
Dino Digs was released on DVD and Digital HD on May 10, 2016.
It was followed by The Big Fur-eeze, which was released on November 8, 2016.
The final installment, Journey to Bear Kingdom was
released on DVD and Digital HD on May 9, 2017.
The film explores themes of wolf, arranged
marriage, forbidden love, road trip, park.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.